## Pamela Welch

Troy, NY 12180 • pamwelch98@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/pamela-welch • 518-626-1367

#### MARKETING AND COMMUNICATIONS LEADER

Proven professional with extensive experience in all facets of communication and marketing. Expert in traditional and social media, photo shoots, and production of digital marketing campaigns, television, radio, and print advertising. Skilled in content creation, oversight of creative design, and project management.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# St. Peter's Health Partners, Albany, NY — Marketing and Communications Manager October 2011 - July 2020

- Managed and implemented marketing and communications activities for St. Peter's Health Partners Corporate, Acute Care, and Continuing Care divisions.
- Developed and implemented marketing and communication strategies in collaboration with the communications team.
- Drafted and edited newsletters, collateral materials, digital marketing materials, direct mail, print, and broadcast advertising.
- Populated and maintained content of the consumer website.
- Developed, implemented, and evaluated social media and digital marketing strategies.
- Directed photo shoots and oversaw the production of digital marketing and social media campaigns, television, radio, and print advertising.
- Coordinated events.

### Northeast Health, Troy, NY — Marketing Manager/ Marketing Coordinator November 1999 - September 2011

In 2011, Northeast Health merged with St. Peter's Hospital in Albany and St. Mary's Hospital in Troy creating St. Peter's Health Partners. My scope of work was similar to that which is described under St. Peter's Health Partners.

# **Community Care Physicians, Latham, NY** — **Coordinator of Marketing Services** October 1997 - October 1999

- Coordinated corporate marketing initiatives and promotion of individual practices.
- Designed advertising and collateral materials.
- Oversaw consumer website development.

# Albany Memorial Hospital, Albany, NY — Planning and Marketing Coordinator September 1995 -April 1997

 Planned, created, and implemented marketing strategies for various departments including a network of primary care practices.

### Luyk, Miller, Pelton Advertising, Schenectady, NY — Media Director

June 1991 - August 1995

- Developed integrated marketing strategies and oversaw all aspects of the agency's media department.
- Planned and implemented television, radio, print, outdoor, and direct mail buys.
- Served as a liaison between media representatives, the agency, and its clients.

### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Arts: Public Communications, Minor in Computer Science - College of St. Rose, Albany, NY

### **ADDITIONAL ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

- -American Marketing Association's Digital Marketing Exam Prep class
- Northeast Health Leadership and Development Program
- -Management Development Silver Certificate (Northeast Health)
- -Girl Scout Leader for eight years